# Xin JIN

## 5/F, Run Run Shaw Creative Media Centre, 18 Tat Hong Avenue, Kowloon Tong, Hong Kong

E-mail: xin.jin@my.cityu.edu.hk, xjin.comm@gmail.com Mobile: +852 57499397

## **Profile**

The research I have done before includes popular culture, semeiology, media and gender, and ideology analysis. I am proficient in many types of video producing, especially in documentary, creative micro film, interview and news comment. I have a strong desire to try new things in both academy and practice in the future.

## **Education**

City University of Hong KongHong Kong, ChinaM.A. in Communication and New Media-Media Data Analytics Stream2018-Present

Fudan UniversityShanghai, ChinaF.I.S.T. Summer School in Quantitative Communication Research MethodJul 2018

Shanghai Jiao Tong UniversityShanghai, ChinaCommunication Elite Seminar in New Media and Big DataJul 2017

Jinan University & Northwestern University & BBC

Workshop for Media Leaders

Guangzhou, Guangdong, China

Jul 2015

Central South UniversityChangsha, Hunan, ChinaB.A. (with honors) in Radio and Television2014-2018

## Research

#### Project

The Mechanism of How Self-media Influences People's Cognition and Code of Conduct
(National-level S.R.T.P. Fund, Project#201610533241, 10,000 CNY)

Mar 2017

Jun 2017

## Responsibility

Leader

Research method and questionnaire designing, ideology and myth analysis

#### Achievement

Award for Excellent Academic Innovation Project Award for Excellent Academic Innovation Paper

#### Analysis of Web Texts of Social Hot Events

(Provincial Social Science Foundation of China)

Participant of instructor's project (Dr. Huang) Leader of 'Wei Zexi event' text analysis group Analysis of dominant reading

# Xin JIN

## Study of Violent Narration in Current Mass Culture

Aug 2017

(Provincial Social Science Foundation of China)

Participant of instructor's project (Dr. Huang) Semiotic analysis of language violence, behavior violence and environment violence of 10 popular movies

## • Research Experience

#### Research Assistant

(Project#9042463, Prof. Fen Lin, Dept Media & Communication, City U) Jan 2019-Present

## The Rank of School / Department in Communication and Media Study Around the World

(Research Intern, Prof. Jonathan J.H. Zhu, Web Mining Lab, City U) Oct 2018-Present

New Bottle of New Wine or Old Bottle of New Wine: The Comparison of Computational Communication Research and Non-computational Communication Research

Nov 2018
(Research Intern, Web Mining Lab, Prof. Jonathan J.H. Zhu)

## Conference

Jin, X., Ye, Q. Y. (05/01/2019). Impact of Different Social Media Context on Attitude Polarization of Hot Topic Online. *The 1st CUC Ph.D Students Academic Forum on New Media*, Communication University of China, Beijing, China.

## **Professional Achievement**

#### You Young New Media Studio

*Mar 2018* 

(National-level S.E.T.P. Fund, Project#201810533586, 10,000 CNY)

#### Responsibility

Leader & Founder

#### Achievement

Award for Excellent Entrepreneurship Practice Project

Second Award in 'Shenghua Cup' Competition of Science and Technology (Cultural and Creative Industry Track)

#### Film Works

#### National College Students' Sports Micro Film Contest

Top 10 prize-Zero Distance with Rio Olympic Champions

#### National Cross-strait College Students Visual Works Exhibition

1st prize-Days of Being Sorrowful (Cantonese)

#### National Medical Health Science Micro Video Contest

Grand prize-How to Dress Correctly for Newborns

#### Hunan Radio & Television Program Contest, Hunan Satellite TV

3rd prize-Changsha on the Fingertip

# Xin JIN

## The 5th Hunan College Student Art Exhibition

3rd prize-Talk to Myself (Cantonese)

## Hunan TV & Radio College Association TV Program Contest

1st prize-Seniors Speaking from the Bottom of the Heart 2nd prize-Long Drum from the Distant Mountain 3rd prize-the Battle in Millimeters (Hand-made Contest of Clinical Medical Students)

## **Honors and Awards**

Distinction Bachelor Graduate Award, Central South University	Jun 2018
National Scholarship, Ministry of Education of P.R.C	Nov 2017
Excellent Academic Innovation Individual, Office of Innovation of CSU	May 2017
Second-class Scholarship, Central South University	Nov 2015, Nov 2016

## **Skills**

SPSS-Skilled, Python-Fundamental, Power Point-Proficient, Word-Proficient Excel-Skilled, Adobe Premiere-Professional